HARRISON ITOTIA

www.linkedin.com/in/harrison-itotia

https://github.com/ItotiaHarrison

September 2017 - September 2021

June 2022 - February 2023

SUMMARY

Am a Junior software developer keen to get real-world experience and help a dynamic software development team succeed. Having a firm grounding in the fundamentals of software development and programming languages like Javascript and Python, I'm excited to put my knowledge in use and continue to develop my abilities in a work setting.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern | ITALANTA

January 2023 - April 2023 | Nairobi, Kenya

- Contributing to an open-source project.
- Create and use reusable components.
- Page routing.
- Ensuring the components are web responsive.

Technologies/skills: Angular, Typescript

Software Developer Intern | SASAKAZI

April 2023 - Present | Nairobi, Kenya

Deployed to Beyond my tribe organization to intern as a software developer.

- Integrating a payment system for their donation site.
- Creating functional pages for their site.

Technologies/skills: Javascript, React, Bootstrap CSS

EDUCATION

University of Nairobi

Bachelor of Science in STATISTICS

Undergraduate coursework: Probability and Statistics, Computational methods and data analysis

Moringa School

Certificate for completion

 Completed the Software engineering course: Git, Linux, HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Ruby, Rails, SQLite, Soft skills

PROJECTS

- <u>Riziki Job Application portal</u> A web application that allows freelancers to look for job opportunities while employers post jobs and hire freelancers.
- **Elewa -** An open-source project for a website for the Elewa programme under Italanta.
- <u>Electric car battery range calculator</u> A site to calculate how long an electric car battery would last under different conditions.
- Beyond My Tribe A website for a Kenyan initiative that focuses on promoting youth involvement and development.

TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS

- Javascript, React.Js, Angular.Js, SQLite, Ruby on Rails Git, Github, Render, Vercel
- Data analysis: Python, R